{"id":"2017_6","name":"Romans2017_6","memoryVerse":"“This righteousness is given through faith in Jesus Christ to all who believe. There is no difference between Jew and Gentile, for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God.” – Romans 3:22-23 ","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2017_6_1","questionText":"1. What was meaningful to you in the lecture?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_6_2","questionText":"2. What help did you receive from the notes?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read Romans 3:27-28.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:27-28"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_6_3","questionText":"3. How do people today boast about their spirituality or relationship with God, and why is all boasting to be excluded?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_6_4","questionText":"4. Name some different ways people try to justify themselves before God. Which one most accurately applies to the way you live?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_6_5","questionText":"5. What is wrong with people’s hearts and relationships when they boast of their own righteousness, and how can you guard against self-righteousness?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read Romans 3:27-28.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:27-28"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_6_6","questionText":"6. List various ways people today understand and use the word “faith.” ","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_6_7a","questionText":"7. a.  Read Hebrews 11. Describe in your own words the kind of faith that justifies or saves a person. (You may use any Scripture references to support your answer.) List some things these believers’ faith caused them to do.","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Hebrews","verse":"11:1-40"}]},{"id":"2017_6_7b","questionText":"7. b. Share something your faith has recently prompted you to do.","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read Romans 3:29-30.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:29-30"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_6_8","questionText":"8.  Who are Gentiles, and why would Jews in Paul’s day look down on them? (See Romans 2:17, 23, 25. Use a  dictionary if necessary.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"2:17"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"2:23"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"2:25"}]},{"id":"2017_6_9","questionText":"9. How does the fact that “there is only one God” and one way of salvation compare with how many people  think today?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_6_10","questionText":"10. What truths from this passage or previous lessons could you use to respond graciously to people who say all  religions are true or there are many gods or many ways to God? ","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Romans 3:31.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:31"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_6_11","questionText":"11.  How does faith uphold the law? (See Exodus 20:1-17; Romans 8:3-4; 13:8-10.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Exodus","verse":"20:1-17"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:3-4"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"13:8-10"}]},{"id":"2017_6_12","questionText":"12. Give examples of what goes wrong when people in the church believe they do not need to obey God’s commands and also teach others to disobey. (This thinking is called “antinomianism.”) (See also Jude 1:4.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Jude","verse":"1:4"}]},{"id":"2017_6_13","questionText":"13.  If  God has justified you through faith, give examples of how He encourages and enables you to obey Him.  (See Romans 8:12-17, 31-34; Philippians 2:12-13; 1 John 1:5-10.)  ","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:12-17"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:31-34"},{"book":"Philippians","verse":"2:12-13"},{"book":"1 John","verse":"1:5-10"}]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review Romans 3:27-31.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:27-31"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_6_14","questionText":"14. What have you learned about God in this week’s study? How may your group pray for you as you make this truth a part of your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}